Guide to the Denise Levertov Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2. Manuscripts
  - a. Poetry
    - "Consulting with the desperate turtles", c. 1966, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Good Talk By the Fireside, c. 1966, 1 AMs, 2 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - "In the arroyo, where the green bushes grow", c. 1967 - 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - "Just as the Marvel of Pern, summers ago", c. 1966, AMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Making Time, c. 1966, 3 AMs, 3 pp. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - My patio 7 a.m. 1964 Jan. 20 / Childhood Days in S. Wales / Mother's Poems, 1964 Jan. 20, AMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Offering / Lunch Hour, c. 1966, TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Paintings by John Button, c. 1966, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Pleitskaya / To a Song / Sea Clouds / Cold Song, c. 1966, TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Spirit of an Artist Addressed as a Bear, c. 1966, TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - The Contradiction, c. 1966, AMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - The Hired Girl, c. 1966, TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - "The Love Song that Burned the Lips of the New World in 1966", 1966, 1 AMs, 2 TMs (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - The Twins, c. 1966, AMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - The White Coat, c. 1966, TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - "To meet / Thou / not You", c. 1966, AMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Triple Poem for Elaine, c. 1966, TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Visitor, c. 1966, TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Unidentified fragment: "Joy", c. 1966, AMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Unidentified fragments, c. 1966, 3 AMs, 4 pp. (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified fragments, c. 1966, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Unidentified poem, 1966 Jan., TMs, 3 pp. (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Unidentified poem: "Not to have but to be", c. 1966, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Unidentified fragments, c. 1967, 3 AMs, 3 pp. (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - War Resisters League Calendar 1968: Photocopies of poems, 1967, TMs, 59 pp. (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - War Resisters League Calendar 1968: Editor's notes, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - War Resisters League Calendar 1968: Notes, 1967, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - A Tree Telling of Orpheus, 1968, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Notes on Returning the Alphabet, A Tree Telling of Opheus, "Wanting the Moon", 1968 July (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - A New Year's Garland for my Student, 1969 - 1970, AMs, 27 pp. TMs, 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - A New Year's Garland for my Students: Galley Proofs, 1969 - 1970, TMs, 21 pp. (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Notebook: Poems from Relearning the Alphabet and To Stay Alive, 1967 Oct., TMs, 21 pp. (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Notebook: Poems from Relearning the Alphabet, 1966 June - 1968 Oct., TMs, 21 pp. (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Notebook: Fragments, c. 1968 - 1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Baudelaire, n.d., AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Character is Fate, 1960s?, TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - [December 2 a decade closed], c. 1969 - 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Desolate, n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Down Here and Up There, n.d. [c. 1960s], TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Few they are, the lines / that really stick in the memory.", c. 1969, AMs, 4 pp. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Formal reply, n.d. [c. 1960s], 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - From a painting (Ronault) [verso: draft], n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "From love one takes / petal to rock...", n.d. [c. 1960s], AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - George, c. 1962 - 1968, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Grandfather Levertoff grew melons, pondered", c. 1968 - 1970, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 5 pp. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Haiku, 1960s?, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - I Am Afraid For The Roses, c. 1960s, TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "In dream the daidem / of dew-pearls misty in mirrored hair", n.d. [c. 1960s], AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Ingres, c. 1962 - 1968, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "In the quiet room on the TV screen", n.d. [c. 1969?], AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "It is desired that the esteemed professor", n.d., AMs, 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Lemonade, c. 1962 - 1968, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Love is a Babel [2 poems foir Midi Garth], n.d. [c. 1960s?], AMs, 31 pp. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Manners, n.d. [c. 1960s?], 1 AMs (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - May 14 / 15 1969. Berkeley. (Fragment of work in progress), c. 1969, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Neighbor's Troubles, n.d. [c. 1960s], TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - "Olga, Pandora, it was you", c. 1969, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "Parable of Buddha concerning the burning house", n.d., AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - "Pays de Rochers" and "Land of Stone", n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "...poems leaping from shattered windows", c. 1962 - 1968, TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Portrait of Donor, c. 1969, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "Psalm", n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Quatrocento - Passing of Verrochio, c. 1962 - 1968, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Road, Waving to the Devil, End of Summer, 1969 Sept., TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Ruggles Visionary Specre in Vermont, 1968 - 1970, TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - "Samas, Mora, Johnson stand", n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - "Saying my soul's black, what do I mean?", n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Self-Portrait of a Friend, n.d. [c. 1960s], AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Souvenir Trumpet, n.d., AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Stars (Ungaretti), c. 1962 - 1968, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Tables of the Law [People and Things], [c. 1960s], 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 4 pp. (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - The Bicycles, n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - "The butterflies - cowering", n.d. [c. 1960s], AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - The Cricket, c. 1969, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - The Pigeons, n.d. [c. 1960s], AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - "The pride I wanted", c. 1968 - 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - "There is no poem / I would not write for you", n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - The Song, n.d. [c. 1960s], 2 AMs, 8 pp. (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - "The traprock quarry, desolate and useful", n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - "To those born later (to those of a later time)", n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - "To wake them, who have been sleeping...", n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Two in the Aftermath, c. 1962 - 1968, 3 AMs, 3 pp. (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Unidentified fragments, c. 1968 - 1970, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Unidentified fragments, c. 1969, 5 AMs, 5 pp. (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Unidentified fragments, 1960s, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Unidentified fragments, n.d. pc. 1960s], 5 AMs, 5 pp. (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Unidentified fragments, n.d. pc. 1960s], 12 AMs, 17 pp. (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Unidentified fragments, n.d. pc. 1960s], 8 AMs, 8 pp. (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Unidentified fragments, n.d. pc. 1960s], AMs, 4 pp. (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified fragments, n.d. pc. 1960s], 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Unidentified poem, 1960s?, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Unidentified poem, 1960s?, AMs, 4 pp. (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Unidentified poems and fragments, n.d. [c. 1960s] (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: An Interim, 1970, AMs, 6 pp. (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: Biafra, 1970, 3 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: Dance Memories, 1970, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: For Paul and Sally Goodman, 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: From a Notebook, 1968 Oct. - 1969 May (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: Invocation, 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: Relearning the Alphabet, 1970, AMs, 10 pp. (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: Somebody Trying, 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: Souvenir d'amite, 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: The Gulf, 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: The Heart, 1970, 2 AMs, 6 pp. (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: The Open Secret, 1970, 1 AMs, 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: Photographs for the Cover, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - To Stay Alive: Advent 1966, 1966 Dec., TMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - To Stay Alive: An Interim, 1971, AMs, 10 pp. (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - To Stay Alive: Entr'acte [ii. Gandhi's Gun (and Brecht's Vow)] (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - To Stay Alive: Entr'acte [iii. The Year One], 1971, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - To Stay Alive: Entr'acte [iv. Looking for the Devil Poems], 1971, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - To Stay Alive: Entr'acte [v. Today], 1971, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - To Stay Alive: Entr'acte [viii. Revolutionary], 1971, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - To Stay Alive: Entr'acte iii. - ix. [with comments by Galway Kinnell], 1971 summer, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - To Stay Alive: Entr'acte [with comments by Gallway Kinnell], 1971 summer, TMs, 4 pp. AM, 16 pp. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - To Stay Alive: Part II, 1971, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - To Stay Alive: Part III, 1971, 2 AMs, 17 pp. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Notebook, "Part III," from To Stay Alive, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - To Stay Alive: Part III [with comments by Galway Kinnell], 1971 summer, TMs, 16 pp. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - To Stay Alive: Part IV, 1971, 2 AMs, 4 pp. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - To Stay Alive: Part IV [with comments by Galway Kinnell], 1971 summer, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - To Stay Alive: References, 1971, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Footprints (1 of 3), 1972, TMs, 25 pp. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Footprints (2 of 3), 1972, TMs, 39 pp. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Footprints (3 of 3), 1972, TMs, 24 pp. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Footprints: Animal Rights, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Footprints: A Place to Live, 1972, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Footprints: At the 'Mass Ave. Poetry Hawkers' Reading in the Red Book Cellar, 1972, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Footprints: Brass Tacks, 1972, 3 AMs, 5 pp. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Footprints: Earthworks, 1972, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Footprints: Hut, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Footprints: In Silence (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Footprints: Intrusion, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Footprints: Leather Jacket, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Footprints: Life is Not a Walk Across a Field, 1972, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 5 pp. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Footprints: Living with a Painting, 1961 Oct., 1 AMs, 1 TMs (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Footprints: Obstinate Faith, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Footprints: Only Connect, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Footprints: Overhead over S.E. Asia, 1972, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Footprints: Road, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Footprints: Small Sator:, 1972, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Footprints: Sun, Moon, and Stars, 1972, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Footprints: The Day the Audience Walked Out on Me, and Why, 1972, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Footprints: The Footprints, 1972, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Footprints: The Good Dream, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Footprints: The News, 1972, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Footprints: The Old King, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Footprints: The Poem Unwritten, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Footprints: The Rebuff, 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Relearning the Alphabet: The Singer, 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Footprints: The Sun Going Down Upon Our Wrath, 1972, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Footprints: To Antonio Mechado, 1972, AMs, 1 pp. (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Footprints: Folder, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Footprints: Notes and Contents, 1972, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Adapted from Machado, c. 1972, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Anachronistic Poem, c. 1972?, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - A Question from Denise Levertov - London summer 1970, 1970 Summer, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - "At the Justice Department, Nov. 15, 1969", 1970 May, TMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - "Bromige - 'This difficulty of what reason", 1970 Oct., AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Improvisation at Deer Island Prison, 1975 Mar., 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - "In the pinewoods of Lucar", c. 1970, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - "I used to see myself in Venice, Venezia, in winter,", c. 1975, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Last Love, c. 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Literal for Montale, 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Nguyen Dinh Thi - 3 poems from Japan ("Japanese Pictures"), 1970, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - On a Friendship (for R.D.), 1975 Mar. 5, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - "On the Shelf", 1970 Jan. 26, TMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - "O, tell us, poet, what do you do?", c. 1973, AMs, 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - "Out of the dream my living / wonder's like Psycho's", 1970 - 1975?, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Song in the Produce Market, c. 1970, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Souvenir Trumpet, c. 1975, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Taking Hold, 1973 Feb., AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Man Who is Not Charles, 1972, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "Thought I'd be helpless without sight", c. 1972, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified poem, 1975?, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - What 'Liberal' Means, 1970 Apr., AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "While we lie in the road to block traffic", c. 1970, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - notes [on mythology / religion], c. 1971, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Poems, c. 1973 - 1975, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - notes [on poetics], c. 1971, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - reading / talk on Dostoyevsky, c.1973, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - unidentified fragments, c. 1970, 7 AMs, 7 pp. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - unidentified fragments, c. 1970, 3 AMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - unidentified fragments, c. 1975, 3 AMs, 4 pp. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - unidentified fragments, c. 1970, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - unidentified poem, c. 1970, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - unidentified poem, c. 1974?, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - unidentified poems and fragments, c. 1971, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - unidentified poems and fragments, c. 1971, 6 AMs, 6 pp. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - unidentified poems and fragments, c. 1973, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - unidentified poem [on Russia], c. 1971?, AMs, 6 pp. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - The freeing of the dust: A Letter to Marek about a Photograph, 1975, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - The freeing of the dust: A Place of Kindness, 1972 June, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - The Freeing of the Dust: April in Ohio, 1975, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - The freeing of the dust: A Time Past, 1972 July, 2 TMs, 4 pp. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - The freeing of the dust: Cancion, 1975, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - The freeing of the dust: Cloud Poems, 1974, 2 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - The freeing of the dust: Conversation in Moscow, 4 TMs, 4 AMs, 18 pp. (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - The freeing of the dust: Cross purposes, 1975, 2 TMs, 5 pp. (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - The freeing of the dust: Divorcing, 1975, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - The freeing of the dust: Dragon of Revolutionary Love, 1972 / 1973, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - The freeing of the dust: Face, 1975, 3 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - The freeing of the dust: For the Blind, 1975, TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - The freeing of the dust: Fragment, 1972, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - The freeing of the dust: Freedom, 1973 Jan., 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - The freeing of the dust: Grief, 1975, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - The freeing of the dust: Dream Inscape, 1973 July, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - The freeing of the dust: In Summer, 1973 July (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - The freeing of the dust: In Thai Binh (Peace) Province; The Pilots; Fragrance of Life, Odor of Death; The Quality of Genius [originally filed in a folder labelled "M.S.S. Houghton" - see note by DL], c. 1973, 4 AMs, 13 pp. (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - The freeing of the dust: Journeyings, 1975, TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - The freeing of the dust: Living Alone, 1974 May, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - The freeing of the dust: Living Alone (II) [originally titled "Spells"], 1975, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - The freeing of the dust: Living for Two, 1974 May, 2 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - The freeing of the dust: "May Our Right Hands Lose their Cunning", 1975, AMs, 8 pp. (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - The freeing of the dust: Modes of being, 1975, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - The freeing of the dust: Room, 1975, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - The freeing of the dust: Seth Thomas: A Love Poem, 1973 Jan., TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - The freeing of the dust: Seth Thomas: The Balance, 1973 Jan., TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - The freeing of the dust: The Freeing of the Dust, 1975, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - The freeing of the dust: The Life of Others, 1972 fall, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - The freeing of the dust: The Pilots, 1972 Nov., 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - The freeing of the dust: The Quality of Genius, 1973 Nov., TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - The freeing of the dust: The Way It Is, 1975, TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - The freeing of the dust: The Wealth of the Destitute, 1975, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - The freeing of the dust: The Woman, 1975, TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - The freeing of the dust: Too Much to Hope, 1975, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - The freeing of the dust: Voyage, 1975, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - The freeing of the dust: Ways of Conquest, 1973 Apr., 3 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - The freeing of the dust: Weeping Woman, 1975, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - The freeing of the dust: What She Could Not Tell Him, 1974, TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - The freeing of the dust - list of people to recieve copies, 1974, TMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Life in the Forest: A Daughter (I), 1978, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Life in the Forest: A Daughter (II) [includes notes from the American Academy exhibition], 1978, 2 AMs, 5 pp. (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Life in the Forest: Alongside, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Life in the Forest: A Pilgrim Dreaming, 1978, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Life in the Forest: Artist to Intellectual (Poet to Explainer), 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Life in the Forest: A Son, 1978, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - Life in the Forest: A Soul-Cake, 1978, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Life in the Forest: Autumnal, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Life in the Forest: A Woman Meets an Old Lover, 1978, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Life in the Forest: A Woman Pacing Her Room, Rereading a Letter, Returning Again and Again to the Mirror, 1978, 2 AMs, 7 pp. (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - Life in the Forest: A Young Man Travelling, 1978, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Life in the Forest: Blake's Baptismal Font [includes illustrated Guide to St. James Church, Picadilly, and notecard for American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters exhibition], 1978, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Life in the Forest: Death in Mexico, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Life in the Forest: Death Psalm: O Lord of Mysteries, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Life in the Forest: Dream: Chateau de Galais, 1978, AMs, 4 p. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Life in the Forest: Dream: Earliest Spring, 1978, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 4 pp. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Life in the Forest: Emblem (I), A Soul Cake [note by DL c. 1984], 1978, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Life in the Forest: Four Related Pieces [includes "Emblem, I" "Choreography of a Play" and "A Soul Cake"], 1978, TMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Life in the Forest: For Chile, 1977 [includes notecard for American Academy exhibition], 1978, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Life in the Forest: Greeting to the Vietnamese Delegates to the U.N. [includes "To the First Vietnamese Mission to the U.N., Setember 1977, 2 AMs, 1 TMs, 9 pp.], 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Life in the Forest: Intimation, 1978, AMs, 4 pp. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Life in the Forest: Kindness, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Life in the Forest: Life in the Forest, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Life in the Forest: Love Poem, 1978, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Life in the Forest: Magic, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Life in the Forest: Metamorphic Journal, 1978, AMs, 6 pp. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Life in the Forest: Modulations, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Life in the Forest: On the 32nd Anniversary of the Bombing of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, 1978, AMs, 10 pp. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Life in the Forest: Postcard, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Life in the Forest: Silk, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Life in the Forest: Slowly, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Life in the Forest: Talking to Grief [originally titled "One of the Angels"], 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Life in the Forest: The Cabdriver's Smile, 1978, 1 AMs, 1 TMs, 4 pp. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Life in the Forest: The Long Way Round [orginally titled "What I Owe to the Vietnamese"], 1978, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Life in the Forest: The Poet Li Admiring a Waterfall, 1975 Dec., AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Life in the Forest: Wedding-Ring, 1978, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Life in the Forest: Receipt for return of materials lent to the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters for exhibition, n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Above the Cave, n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "A Minor Key? The years of moonlight pass.", 1977 July 8, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Apartment Building i) Looking Thrice ii) A Sound of Fear, 1970s, TMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Choreography of a Day, 1977, revised 1983, AMs, 1 p. AMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - (Class assignment), 1970s, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Confession, c. 1975 - 1980, TMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - "Dad, old dumb lifegiver", c. 1977 - 1980, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - December Sunset, c. 1977 - 1980, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "Deep into the landscape", c. 1975 - 1980, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "Everything is not instead but as well", c. 1976?, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "Face of a wizard, body of a boy", 1976, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "Fading", 1970s, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "For Jon" (includes poems from Life in the Forest and Candles in Babylon), c. 1975?, AMs, 24 pp. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "He was small / and old, and leaped", 1970s, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Imagine the god: with upturned / face of a blind harpen ascending", c. 1975 - 1980, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "In childhood, free to act as I wished", c. 1977 - 1980, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - "In the pain-jungle", c. 1975 - 1980, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - "I pinned the blame upon / those winged shoulders", c. 1975 - 1980, AMs, 1 p. (Box 10, Folder 44)